So far we've been talking about
目前为止 我们在比较抽象的层面上
SVMs in a fairly abstract level.
讨论了支持向量机 SVM
In this video I'd like to
在这段视频中
talk about what you actually need
为了运行 或者说使用 SVM
to do in order to run or to use an SVM.
你实际上需要做什么
The support vector machine algorithm
支持向量机算法
poses a particular optimization problem.
是一个特定的优化问题
But as I briefly mentioned in
但是就如我在之前的
an earlier video, I really
视频中简单提到的
do not recommend writing your
我真的不建议你自己写
own software to solve for the parameter's theta yourself.
软件来求解参数θ
So just as today, very
就像如今只有很少的人
few of us, or maybe almost essentially
或者说根本没有人
none of us would think of
会考虑自己写代码
writing code ourselves to invert a matrix
来实现对矩阵求逆
or take a square root of a number, and so on.
或求一个数的平方根等
We just, you know, call some library function to do that.
我们只要调用库函数来实现这些
In the same way, the
同样地
software for solving the SVM
用以解决 SVM 优化问题
optimization problem is very
的软件很复杂
complex, and there have
而且已经有
been researchers that have been
专门研究数值优化很多年
doing essentially numerical optimization research for many years.
的学者在做这个
So you come up with good
因此你需要好的
software libraries and good software
软件库和好的软件包
packages to do this.
来做这个
And then strongly recommend just using
然后强烈建议使用
one of the highly optimized software
一个高度优化的软件库
libraries rather than trying to implement something yourself.
而不是尝试自己去实现它
And there are lots of good software libraries out there.
有许多好的软件库
The two that I happen to
我最常用的两个是
use the most often are the
liblinear 和 libsvm
linear SVM but there are really
但是真的有很多软件库
lots of good software libraries for
可以用来
doing this that you know, you can
实现这个
link to many of the
你可以在很多主流编程语言
major programming languages that you
可能是你用来写学习算法的语言
may be using to code up learning algorithm.
找到这个软件库
Even though you shouldn't be writing
尽管你不应该去写
your own SVM optimization software,
你自己的 SVM 优化软件
there are a few things you need to do, though.
但是你也需要做几件事儿
First is to come up
首先是
with with some choice of the
要选择参数C
parameter's C. We talked a
我们在之前的视频中
little bit of the bias/variance properties of
讨论误差/方差的性质时
this in the earlier video.
提到过这个
Second, you also need to
第二 你也需要
choose the kernel or the
选择核函数或
similarity function that you want to use.
你想要使用的相似度函数
So one choice might
其中一个选择是
be if we decide not to use any kernel.
我们选择不用任何核函数
And the idea of no kernel
不用核函数这个作法
is also called a linear kernel.
也叫线性核函数
So if someone says, I use
因此 如果有人说
an SVM with a linear kernel,
他的 SVM 用了线性核函数
what that means is you know, they use
这就意味着
an SVM without using without
他在使用 SVM 时
using a kernel and it
没有用核函数
was a version of the SVM
这种用法的 SVM
that just uses theta transpose X, right,
只使用了 θ 转置乘以x
that predicts 1 theta 0
当 θ0 + θ1x1 + ... + θnxn 大于等于0时
N, X N is greater than equals 0.
预测 y=1
This term linear kernel, you
对线性核函数这个术语
can think of this as you know this
你可以把它理解为
is the version of the SVM
这个版本的 SVM
that just gives you a standard linear classifier.
它只是给你一个标准的线性分类器
So that would be one
因此对某些问题来说
reasonable choice for some problems,
它是一个合理的选择
and you know, there would be many software
而且你知道 有许多软件库
libraries, like linear, was
比如 liblinear
one example, out of many,
就是众多软件库
one example of a software library
中的一个例子
that can train an SVM
它们可以用来训练的 SVM
without using a kernel, also
是没有核函数的
called a linear kernel.
也叫线性核函数
So, why would you want to do this?
那么你为什么想要做这样一件事儿呢？
If you have a large number of
如果你有大量的特征变量
features, if N is
如果 n 很大
large, and M the
而训练集的样本数
number of training examples is
m 很小
small, then you know
那么 你知道
you have a huge number of
你有大量的特征变量
features that if X, this is
x 是一个 n+1 维向量
So if you have a
那么如果你已经有
huge number of features already, with
大量的特征值
a small training set, you know, maybe you
和很小的训练数据集
want to just fit a linear
也许你应该拟合
decision boundary and not try
一个线性的判定边界
to fit a very complicated nonlinear
不要拟合非常复杂的非线性函数
function, because might not have enough data.
因为没有足够的数据
And you might risk overfitting, if
如果你想在一个高维特征空间
you're trying to fit a very complicated function
试着拟合非常复杂的函数
in a very high dimensional feature space,
而你的训练集又很小的话
but if your training set sample
你可能会过度拟合
is small. So this
因此 这应该是
would be one reasonable setting where
你可能决定不适用核函数
you might decide to just
或者等价地说使用线性核函数
equivalents to use what's called a linear kernel.
的一个合理情况
A second choice for the kernel that
对于核函数的第二个选择是
you might make, is this Gaussian
这个高斯核函数
kernel, and this is what we had previously.
这个是我们之前见过的
And if you do this, then the
如果你选择这个
other choice you need to make
那么你要做的另外一个选择是
is to choose this parameter sigma squared
选择一个参数σ的平方
when we also talk a little bit about the bias variance tradeoffs
我们之前讨论如何权衡偏差方差的时候谈到过
of how, if sigma squared is
如果 σ 的平方很大
large, then you tend
那么你就有可能
to have a higher bias, lower
得到一个较大的误差
variance classifier, but if
较低方差的分类器
sigma squared is small, then you
但是如果 σ 的平方很小
have a higher variance, lower bias classifier.
那么你就会有较大的方差 较低误差的分类器
So when would you choose a Gaussian kernel?
那么什么时候选择高斯核函数呢？
Well, if your omission
如果你原来的特征变量
of features X, I mean
x 是 n 维的
Rn, and if N
如果 n 很小
is small, and, ideally, you know,
并且 理想情况下
if n is large, right,
如果 m 很大
so that's if, you know, we have
那么如果我们有
say, a two-dimensional training set,
一个二维的训练集
like the example I drew earlier.
就像我前面讲到的例子一样
So n is equal to 2, but we have a pretty large training set.
那么n等于2 但是我们有相当大的训练集
So, you know, I've drawn in a
我已经画出了
fairly large number of training examples,
大量的训练样本
then maybe you want to use
那么可能你需要用
a kernel to fit a more
一个核函数去拟合一个
complex nonlinear decision boundary,
更复杂的非线性判定边界
and the Gaussian kernel would be a fine way to do this.
那么高斯核函数会是不错的选择
I'll say more towards the end
我会在这个视频的后面部分
of the video, a little bit
讲到更多一些关于
more about when you might choose a
什么时候你可以选择
linear kernel, a Gaussian kernel and so on.
线性核函数 高斯核函数等
But if concretely, if you
但是具体地说
decide to use a Gaussian
如果你决定使用高斯核函数
kernel, then here's what you need to do.
那么下面是你需要做的
Depending on what support vector machine
根据你所用的
software package you use, it
支持向量机软件包
may ask you to implement a
它可能需要你
kernel function, or to implement
实现一个核函数
the similarity function.
或者实现相似度函数
So if you're using an
因此 如果你用
octave or MATLAB implementation of
Octave 或者 Matlab 来实现
an SVM, it may ask you
支持向量机的话
to provide a function to
它会要求你提供一个函数
compute a particular feature of the kernel.
来计算核函数的特定特征
So this is really computing f
因此这是对一个特定的 i
particular value of i, where
计算 fi
f here is just a
这里的 f 只是
single real number, so maybe
一个单一的实数
I should move this better written
也许我应该把它写成 fi
f(i), but what you
但是你需要做的是
need to do is to write a kernel
写一个核函数
function that takes this input, you know,
把这个作为输入
a training example or a
一个训练样本
test example whatever it takes
或者一个测试样本
in some vector X and takes
不论是哪个 作为输入的是向量 x
as input one of the
然后把标识点
landmarks and but
也作为一个输入
only I've come down X1 and
在这里我只写了
X2 here, because the
x1 和 x2
landmarks are really training examples as well.
因为标识点也是训练样本
But what you
但是你需要做的是
need to do is write software that
写一个这样的软件
takes this input, you know, X1, X2
它把 x1 x2 作为输入
and computes this sort
然后计算它们之间的
of similarity function between them
这种相似度函数
and return a real number.
之后返回一个实数
And so what some support vector machine
因此一些支持向量机的
packages do is expect
包所做的是期望
you to provide this kernel function
你能提供一个核函数
that take this input you know, X1, X2 and returns a real number.
能够输入 x1 x2 并返回一个实数
And then it will take it from there
从这里开始
and it will automatically generate all the features, and
它将自动地生成所有特征变量
so automatically take X and
它自动地
map it to f1,
用你写的这个函数
f2, down to f(m) using
将 x 映射到对应的
this function that you write, and
f1 f2 一直到 fm
generate all the features and
生成所有的特征值
train the support vector machine from there.
并从这儿开始训练支持向量机
But sometimes you do need to
但是有些时候你却一定要
provide this function yourself.
自己提供这个函数
Other if you are using the Gaussian kernel, some SVM implementations will also include the Gaussian kernel
如果你使用高斯核函数
and a
一些SVM的实现也会包括高斯核函数
few other kernels as well, since
和一些其他的核函数
the Gaussian kernel is probably the most common kernel.
因为高斯核函数可能是最常见的核函数
Gaussian and linear kernels are
目前看来 高斯核函数和线性核函数确实是
really the two most popular kernels by far.
最普遍的核函数
Just one implementational note.
一个实现过程中的注意事项
If you have features of very
如果你有大小很不一样
different scales, it is important
的特征变量
to perform feature scaling before
在使用高斯核函数之前
using the Gaussian kernel.
对它们进行归一化是很重要的
And here's why.
这里有一个
If you imagine the computing
如果假设你在计算
the norm between X and
x 和 l 之间的范数
l, right, so this term here,
就是这样一个式子
and the numerator term over there.
是这里的分子项
What this is doing, the norm
这个式子所算的是
between X and l, that's really
x 和 l 之间的范数
saying, you know, let's compute the vector
就等于说
V, which is equal to
计算一个向量 v
X minus l. And then
这个向量 v=x-l
let's compute the norm does
然后计算向量 v 的范数
vector V, which is the
这也就是 x 和 l 之间的差
norm of V is really
v 的范数等于
equal to V1 squared
v1 的平方
plus V2 squared plus
加 v2 的平方加
dot dot dot, plus Vn squared.
点点点 加 vn 的平方
Because here X is in
因为这里的 x 是 n 维向量
Rn, or Rn
或者说是 n+1 维的
plus 1, but I'm going to ignore, you know, X0.
但是我要忽略 x0
So, let's pretend X is
因此我们假设
an Rn, square on
x 是 n 维向量
the left side is what makes this correct.
在左边加上平方就是正确的了
So this is equal
因此这个式子就等于
to that, right?
那个式子 对吧？
And so written differently, this is
那么另一种不同的写法就是
going to be X1 minus l1
(x1-l1)^2+(x2-l2)^2+...+(xn-ln)^2
And now if your features
现在如果你的特征变量
take on very different ranges of value.
取值范围很不一样
So take a housing
就拿房价预测来举例
prediction, for example, if
如果你的数据
your data is some data about houses.
是一些关于房子的数据
And if X is in the
如果特征向量 x 的
range of thousands of square
第一个变量 x1 的取值
feet, for the
在上千平方英尺
first feature, X1.
的范围内
But if your second feature, X2 is the number of bedrooms.
但是如果你的第二个特征变量 x2 是卧室的数量
So if this is in the
且如果它在
range of one to five bedrooms, then
一到五个卧室范围内
X1 minus l1 is going to be huge.
那么 x1-l1 将会很大
This could be like a thousand squared,
这有可能上千数值的平方
whereas X2 minus l2
然而 x2-l2
is going to be much smaller and if
将会变得很小
that's the case, then in this term,
在这样的情况下的话 那么在这个式子中
those distances will be almost
这些间距将几乎
essentially dominated by the
都是由
sizes of the houses
房子的大小来决定的
and the number of bathrooms would be largely ignored.
从而忽略了卧室的数量
As so as, to avoid this in
为了避免这种情况
order to make a machine work
让向量机得以很好地工作
well, do perform future scaling.
确实需要对特征变量进行归一化
And that will sure that the SVM
这将会保证SVM
gives, you know, comparable amount of attention
能够同等地关注到
to all of your different features,
所有不同的特征变量
and not just to in
而不是像例子中那样
this example to size of
只关注到房子的大小
houses were big movement here the features.
而忽略了其他的特征变量
When you try a support vector
当你尝试支持向量机时
machines chances are by
目前为止你可做的选择是
far the two most common
这两个可能是你
kernels you use will
最常用的核函数
be the linear kernel, meaning no
线性核函数 也就是不用核函数
kernel, or the Gaussian kernel that we talked about.
或者我们讨论的高斯核函数
And just one note of warning
这里有一个警告
which is that not all similarity
不是所有你可能提出来
functions you might come up
的相似度函数
with are valid kernels.
都是有效的核函数
And the Gaussian kernel and the linear
高斯核函数 线性核函数
kernel and other kernels that you
以及其他人有时会用到的
sometimes others will use, all
另外的核函数
of them need to satisfy a technical condition.
它们全部需要满足一个技术条件
It's called Mercer's Theorem and
它叫作默塞尔定理 (Mercer's Theorem)
the reason you need to this
需要满足这个条件的原因是
is because support vector machine
因为支持向量机算法
algorithms or implementations of the
或者 SVM 的实现
SVM have lots of clever
有许多巧妙的
numerical optimization tricks.
数值优化技巧
In order to solve for the
为了有效地求解
parameter's theta efficiently and
参数 θ
in the original design envisaged,
在最初的设想里
those are decision made to restrict
有一个这样的决定
our attention only to kernels
将我们的注意力仅仅限制在
that satisfy this technical condition called Mercer's Theorem.
可以满足默塞尔定理的核函数上
And what that does is, that
这个定理所做的是
makes sure that all of these
确保所有的SVM包
SVM packages, all of these SVM
所有的SVM软件包
software packages can use the
能够使用
large class of optimizations and
大量的优化方法
get the parameter theta very quickly.
并且快速地得到参数 θ
So, what most people end up doing
大多数人最后做的是
is using either the linear
要么用线性核函数
or Gaussian kernel, but there
要么用高斯核函数
are a few other kernels that also
但是还有一些其他核函数
satisfy Mercer's theorem and
满足默塞尔定理
that you may run across other
你可能会遇到其他人使用这些核函数
people using, although I personally
然而我个人
end up using other kernels you know, very, very rarely, if at all.
最后是很少很少使用其他核函数
Just to mention some of the other kernels that you may run across.
只是简单提及一下你可能会遇到的其他核函数
One is the polynomial kernel.
一个是多项式核函数
And for that the similarity between
它将 x 和 l 之间的相似度
defined as, there are
定义为
a lot of options, you can
这里有很多种选择
take X transpose l squared.
你可以用 x 的转置乘以 I 的平方
So, here's one measure of how similar X and l are.
那么这就是一个 x 和 l 相似度的估量
If X and l are very close with
如果 x 和 l 相互之间很接近
each other, then the inner product will tend to be large.
那么这个内积就会很大
And so, you know, this is a slightly
这是一个有些
unusual kernel.
不寻常的核函数
That is not used that often, but
它并不那么常用
you may run across some people using it.
但是你可能会见到有人使用它
This is one version of a polynomial kernel.
这是多项式核函数的一个变体
Another is X transpose l cubed.
另一个是 x 转置乘以 I 的立方
These are all examples of the polynomial kernel.
这些都是多项式核函数的例子
X transpose l plus 1 cubed.
x 转置乘以 l 加 1 的立方
X transpose l plus maybe
x 转置乘以 l 加上
a number different then one 5
一个不是 1 的数 比如 5
and, you know, to the power of 4 and
的4次方
so the polynomial kernel actually has two parameters.
多项式核函数实际上有两个参数
One is, what number do you add over here?
一个是你在这里要加的数
It could be 0.
可能是0
This is really plus 0 over there, as well as what's the degree of the polynomial over there.
这里就是加的0 同样地 另一个参数是多项式的次数
So the degree power and these numbers.
参数就是多项式的次数和这些数字
And the more general form of the
多项式核函数的更一般形式是
transpose l, plus some
x 转置乘以 l 加上一个常数
to some degree in the
的某个指数次方
X1 and so both
因此这两个
of these are parameters for the polynomial kernel.
都是多项式核函数的参数
So the polynomial kernel almost always
所以多项式核函数几乎总是
or usually performs worse.
或者通常执行的效果
And the Gaussian kernel does not
比高斯核函数差一些
use that much, but this is just something that you may run across.
所以用得没有那么多 但是你有可能会碰到
Usually it is used only for
通常它只用在
data where X and l
当 x 和 l
are all strictly non negative,
都是严格的非负数时
and so that ensures that these
这样以保证这些
inner products are never negative.
内积值永远不会是负数
And this captures the intuition that
这扑捉到了这样一个直观感觉
X and l are very similar
如果 x 和 l 之间非常相似
to each other, then maybe the inter product between them will be large.
也许它们之间的内积会很大
They have some other properties as well
它们也有其他的一些性质
but people tend not to use it much.
但是人们通常用得不多
And then, depending on what you're
那么 根据你所做的
doing, there are other, sort of more
你也有可能会碰到
esoteric kernels as well, that you may come across.
其它一些更加难懂的核函数
You know, there's a string kernel, this
比如字符串核函数
is sometimes used if your
如果你的输入数据是文本字符串
input data is text strings or other types of strings.
或者其他类型的字符串 有时会用到这个核函数
There are things like the
还有一些函数
chi-square kernel, the histogram intersection kernel, and so on.
如卡方核函数 直方图交叉核函数 等等
There are sort of more esoteric kernels that
还有一些难懂的核函数
you can use to measure similarity
你可以用它们来估量
between different objects.
不同对象之间的相似性
So for example, if you're trying to
例如 如果你在尝试
do some sort of text classification
做一些文本分类的问题
problem, where the input
在这个问题中
x is a string then
输入变量 x 是一个字符串
maybe we want to find the
我们想要通过
similarity between two strings
字符串核函数来找到
using the string kernel, but I
两个字符串间的相似度但是我
personally you know end up very rarely,
但是我个人很少用
if at all, using these more esoteric kernels. I
这些更加难懂的核函数
think I might have use the chi-square
我想我平生可能
kernel, may be once in
用过一次卡方核函数
my life and the histogram kernel,
可能用过一次或者两次
may be once or twice in my life. I've
直方图交叉核函数
actually never used the string kernel myself. But in
我实际上没用过字符串核函数
case you've run across this in other applications. You know, if
只是以防万一你在其他应用中碰到它们
you do a quick web
如果你在网上查一下的话
search we do a quick Google
用 Google 搜索
search or quick Bing search
或者用 Bing 搜索
you should have found definitions that these are the kernels as well. So
你会发现这些也是核函数的定义
just two last details I want to talk about in this video. One in multiclass classification. So, you
我想要在这个视频里讨论最后两个细节
have four classes or more generally
一个是在多类分类中 你有4个类别
3 classes output some appropriate
或者更一般地说是 K 个类别
decision bounday between your multiple classes. Most SVM, many SVM
怎样让 SVM 输出各个类别间合适的判定边界？
packages already have built-in
大部分 SVM 许多 SVM 包已经内置了
multiclass classification functionality. So
多类分类的函数了
if your using a pattern like
因此如果你用的是那种软件包
that, you just use the
你可以直接用内置函数
should work fine. Otherwise,
应该可以工作得很好
one way to do this
不然的话 另一个方式是
is to use the one
一对多 (one-vs.-all) 方法
versus all method that we
这个我们在
talked about when we are developing logistic regression. So
讲解逻辑回归的时候讨论过
what you do is you trade
所以你要做的是
kSVM's if you have
要训练 K 个 SVM
k classes, one to distinguish
如果你有 K 个类别的话
each of the classes from the rest.
每一个 SVM 把一个类同其他类区分开
And this would give you k parameter
这会给你 K 个参数向量
vectors, so this will
它们是
give you, upi lmpw. theta 1, which
θ(1) 它把 y=1  这类
one from all of
和所有其他类别区分开
get the second parameter, vector
然后得到第二个参数向量 θ(2)
you get when you, you know, have
它是在 y=2 为正类
and all the others as negative class
其他类为负类时得到的
and so on up to
以此类推
a parameter vector theta k,
一直到参数向量θ(K)
which is the parameter vector for
是用于
distinguishing the final class
区分最后一个类别 类别 K
key from anything else, and
和其他类别的参数向量
then lastly, this is exactly
最后 这就与
the same as the one versus
我们在逻辑回归中用到的
all method we have for logistic regression.
一对多方法一样
Where we you just predict the class
在逻辑回归中我们只是
i with the largest theta
取使得 θ(i) 转置乘以 x 最大的类 i
transpose X.  So let's multiclass classification designate.
以上是多类分类方法
For the more common cases
对于更为常见的情况
that there is a good
很有可能的是
chance that whatever software package
不论你使用什么软件包
you use, you know, there will be
都很有可能
a reasonable chance that are already
已经内置了
have built in multiclass classification functionality,
多类分类的函数功能
and so you don't need to worry about this result.
因此你不必担心这个
Finally, we developed support vector
最后 我们从逻辑回归开始
machines starting off with logistic
修改了一下代价函数
regression and then modifying the cost function a little bit.
从而得到了支持向量机
The last thing we want to do in this video is, just say a little bit about.
最后我想要在这个视频中讨论一点的是
when you will use one of
对这两个算法
these two algorithms, so let's
你什么时候应该用哪个呢？
say n is the number
假设 n 是特征变量的个数
of features and m is the number of training examples.
m 是训练样本数
So, when should we use one algorithm versus the other?
那么我们什么时候用哪一个呢？
Well, if n is larger
如果 n 相对于你的训练集大小来说较大时
size, so for example,
比如
if you take a business
如果特征变量的数量
much larger than m and this
远大于 m
might be, for example, if you
这可以是 比如说
have a text classification problem, where
如果你有一个文本分类的问题
you know, the dimension of the feature
特征向量的维数
vector is I don't know, maybe, 10 thousand.
我不知道 有可能是1万
And if your training
且如果你的训练集大小
set size is maybe 10
可能是 10
you know, maybe, up to 1000.
可能最多 1000
So, imagine a spam
想象一下垃圾邮件
classification problem, where email
的分类问题 在这个问题中
spam, where you have 10,000
你有1万个特征变量
features corresponding to 10,000 words
对应于1万个单词
but you have, you know, maybe 10
但是你可能有 10 个训练样本
training examples or maybe up to 1,000 examples.
可能最多 1000 个样本
So if n is large relative to
如果 n 相对 m 来说
m, then what I
比较大的话
would usually do is use logistic
我通常会使用逻辑回归
regression or use it
或者使用
as the m without a kernel or
没有核函数的 SVM
use it with a linear kernel.
或者叫线性核函数
Because, if you have so many
因为 如果你有许多特征变量
features with smaller training sets, you know,
而有相对较小的训练集
a linear function will probably
一个线性函数就可能工作得不错
do fine, and you don't have
而且你也没有
really enough data to
足够的数据
fit a very complicated nonlinear function.
来拟合非常复杂的非线性函数
Now if is n is
现在如果 n 较小
small and m is
而 m 是中等大小
intermediate what I mean
我的意思是
by this is n is
n 可以取
maybe anywhere from 1 - 1000, 1 would be very small.
1 - 1000之间的任何数 1是很小的
But maybe up to 1000
也许也会到1000个特征
features and if
如果训练样本的数量
examples is maybe anywhere from
可能是从
10, you know, 10 to maybe up to 10,000 examples.
10 也许是到10,000个样本之间的任何一个值
Maybe up to 50,000 examples.
也许多达5万个样本
If m is pretty big like maybe 10,000 but not a million.
所以 m 挺大的 可能是1万 但不是一百万
Right? So if m is an
因此如果 m 大小适中的话
intermediate size then often
那么通常线性核函数的SVM会工作得很好
an SVM with a linear kernel will work well.
那么通常高斯核函数的SVM会工作得很好
We talked about this early as
这个我们在这之前也讨论过
well, with the one concrete example,
举一个具体的例子
this would be if you have
如果你有一个
a two dimensional training set. So, if n
二维的训练集
is equal to 2 where you
所以 n=2
have, you know, drawing in a pretty large number of training examples.
画上很多训练样本
So Gaussian kernel will do
高斯核函数可以
a pretty good job separating positive and negative classes.
很好地把正类和负类区分开来
One third setting that's of
第三种值得关注的情况是
small but m is large.
如果 n 很小 但是 m 很大
So if n is you know, again maybe
如果 n 还是
1 to 1000, could be larger.
1到1000之间的数 可能会更大一点
But if m was, maybe
但是如果 m 是
50,000 and greater to millions.
5万 或者更大 大到上百万
So, 50,000, a 100,000, million, trillion.
5万 10万 一百万 二百万
You have very very large training set sizes, right.
你有很大很大的训练集
So if this is the case,
如果是这样的情况
then a SVM of the
那么高斯核函数的支持向量机
Gaussian Kernel will be somewhat slow to run.
运行起来就会很慢
Today's SVM packages, if you're
如今的 SVM 包
using a Gaussian Kernel, tend to struggle a bit.
如果使用高斯核函数的话 会很慢
If you have, you know, maybe 50
如果你有5万 那还可以
thousands okay, but if you
但是如果你有
have a million training examples, maybe
一百万个训练样本
or even a 100,000 with a
或者是十万个
massive value of m. Today's
m 的值很大
SVM packages are very good,
如今的 SVM 包很好
but they can still struggle
但是如果你对一个
a little bit when you have a
很大很大的训练集
massive, massive trainings that size when using a Gaussian Kernel.
使用高斯核函数的话 它们还是会有些慢
So in that case, what I
在这种情况下
would usually do is try to just
我经常会做的是
manually create have more
尝试手动地创建
features and then use
更多的特征变量
logistic regression or an SVM
然后使用逻辑回归
without the Kernel.
或者不带核函数的 SVM
And in case you look at this
你看这张幻灯片
slide and you see logistic regression
你看到了逻辑回归
or SVM without a kernel.
或者不带核函数的 SVM
In both of these places, I
在这个两个地方都出现了
kind of paired them together. There's
我把它们放在一起
a reason for that, is that
是有原因的
logistic regression and SVM without
逻辑回归和不带核函数的 SVM
the kernel, those are really pretty
它们都是非常
similar algorithms and, you know, either
相似的算法
logistic regression or SVM
不管是逻辑回归
without a kernel will usually do
还是不带核函数的 SVM
pretty similar things and give
它们会做相似的事情
pretty similar performance, but depending
并且表现也相似
on your implementational details, one may be more efficient than the other.
但是根据你实现的具体情况 其中一个可能会比另一个更加有效
But, where one of
但是如果其中一个算法适用的话
regression where SVM without a
逻辑回归或不带核函数的 SVM
kernel, the other one is to likely
那么另一个算法
to work pretty well as well.
也很有可能工作得很好
But along with the power of
但是 SVM 的威力
the SVM is when you
随着你用不同的核函数学习
use different kernels to learn
复杂的非线性函数
complex nonlinear functions.
而发挥出来
And this regime, you know, when you
在这个区间
have maybe up to 10,000 examples, maybe up to 50,000.
你有多达1万 或者多达5万的样本
And your number of features,
而特征变量的数量
this is reasonably large.
这是相当大的
That's a very common regime
那是一个非常常见的区间
and maybe that's a regime
也许在这个区间下
where a support vector machine with a kernel kernel will shine.
高斯核函数的支持向量机会表现得相当突出
You can do things that are much
你可以做对逻辑回归来说
harder to do that will need logistic regression.
会困难得多的事情
And finally, where do neural networks fit in?
最后 神经网络应该在什么时候使用呢？
Well for all of these
对于所有的这些问题
problems, for all of
对于所有这些区间
designed neural network is likely to work well as well.
一个设计得很好的神经网络也很可能会非常有效
The one disadvantage, or the one
它的一个缺点是
reason that might not sometimes use
或者说有时可能不会使用
the neural network is that,
神经网络的原因是
for some of these problems, the
对于许多这样的问题
neural network might be slow to train.
神经网络训练起来可能会很慢
But if you have a very good
但是如果你有一个非常好的
SVM implementation package, that
SVM实现包
could run faster, quite a bit faster than your neural network.
它会运行得比较快 比神经网络快很多
And, although we didn't show this
尽管我们在此之前没有证明过
earlier, it turns out that
实际上 SVM 的优化问题
SVM has is a convex
是一种凸优化问题
optimization problem and so the
因此好的
good SVM optimization software
SVM 优化软件包
packages will always find
总是会找到
the global minimum or something close to it.
全局最小值 或者接近它的值
And so for the SVM you don't need to worry about local optima.
对于SVM 你不需要担心局部最优
In practice local optima aren't
在实际应用中 局部最优
a huge problem for neural networks
对神经网络来说不是非常大
but they all solve, so this
但是也不小
is one less thing to worry about if you're using an SVM.
所以你在使用 SVM 的时候可以少担心一个问题
And depending on your problem, the neural
根据你的问题
network may be slower, especially
神经网络可能会比 SVM 慢
in this sort of regime than the SVM.
尤其是在这个区间内
In case the guidelines they gave
如果你觉得这里给出的参考
here, seem a little bit vague
看上去有些模糊
and if you're looking at some problems, you know,
如果你在考虑一些问题
the guidelines are a bit
觉得这些参考有一些模糊
vague, I'm still not entirely
我仍然不能完全确定
sure, should I use this
我是该用这个算法
algorithm or that algorithm, that's actually okay.
还是该用那个算法 这个其实没关系
When I face a machine learning
当我遇到机器学习问题时
problem, you know, sometimes its actually
有时确实不清楚
just not clear whether that's the
是不是最好用那个算法
you saw in the earlier videos, really,
但是你在之前的视频中看到的
you know, the algorithm does
算法确实很重要
matter, but what often matters
但是通常更重要的是
even more is things like, how much data do you have.
你有多少数据
And how skilled are you, how
你有多熟练
good are you at doing error
是否擅长做误差分析
analysis and debugging learning
和调试学习算法
algorithms, figuring out how
想出如何设计新的特征变量
figuring out what other features to give you learning algorithms and so on.
以及找出应该输入给学习算法的其它特征变量等方面
And often those things will matter
通常这些方面会比
more than what you are
你使用逻辑回归
using logistic regression or an SVM.
还是 SVM 这方面更加重要
But having said that,
但是 已经说过了
the SVM is still widely
SVM 仍然被广泛认为是
perceived as one of
最强大的学习算法之一
there is this regime of when there's
而且 SVM 在一个区间内
a very effective way to learn complex non linear functions.
是一个非常有效地学习复杂非线性函数的方法
And so I actually, together with
因此 我实际上
logistic regressions, neural networks, SVM's,
逻辑回归 神经网络 SVM 加在一起
using those to speed
有了这三个学习算法
very well positioned to build
我想你已经具备了
state of the art you know,
在广泛的应用里
machine learning systems for a wide
构建最前沿的
region for applications and this
机器学习系统的能力
is another very powerful tool to have in your arsenal.
它是你的武器库中的另一个非常强大的工具
One that is used all
它被广泛地应用在很多地方
over the place in Silicon Valley,
比如在硅谷
or in industry and in
在工业界
the Academia, to build many
在学术等领域来建立许多
high performance machine learning system.
高性能的机器学习系统 【教育无边界字幕组】翻译：星星之火 校对：竹二个 审核：所罗门捷列夫